Guide to the Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records,.
Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records,.
16-4-4213
Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies.
59
Manuals, reports, publications, photographs and roll film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists mainly of the actual film reels used for interpretation and research. Air photos and roll film from miscellaneous projects conducted by Cornell faculty for engineering projects, such as road siting, railroads, landslide analysis, etc. Sites include Bahamas, Brazil, Canada, Guatemala, New Guinea, Panama, & Puerto Rico and others.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records also known as the Cornell Center for Integrated Aerial Photography Studies was founded and directed by Professor Donald J. Belcher. The Center was an interdisciplinary program that focused on practical uses of aerial photography. Aerial photographic interpretation done within the program was used by departments across the University. Examples of research included technical work on optics and instrumentation was done in the College of Engineering, research on soils, pollution, and agronomy, in the College of Agriculture, geology in Arts and Sciences and land planning by the College of Architecture. Research from the lab also had military applications. The program evolved to include satellite remote sensing.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists mainly of the actual film reels used for interpretation and research. Air photos and roll film from miscellaneous projects conducted by Cornell faculty for engineering projects, such as road siting, railroads, landslide analysis, etc. Sites include Bahamas, Brazil, Canada, Guatemala, New Guinea, Panama, & Puerto Rico and others.
Roll film from the Skylab project. Photos from the spacecraft acquired by Cornell for use in determining how well the airphoto analysis techniques developed at Cornell could be applied to imagery collected at satellite altitudes. Most of the rolls are 2.5" format from the S190A camera, but there are a number of 5" and 9" format rolls. Details of the project and inventory of the images can be found in the NASA publication Skylab Earth Resources Data Catalog.
Roll film from a 1970s Environmental Protection Agency project studying drainage and eutrophication in the Finger Lakes. Some of this imagery is described in the volume Inventory of Aerial Photography and other Remotely Sense Imagery of New York State 1968-1983. Includes Canadarago, Cayuga, Great Gully, Onondaga, Owasco, and Skaneateles.
Landform Series material. Training manuals put together for the U.S. military for training in airphoto interpretation, specifically landform analysis. There are several copies of this document, some complete, others not. All of the photos are hand-glued into the pages and many of the photos have come unglued. Includes information on observation of sedimentary rock, igneous rock, metamorphic rock, waterlaid materials, glacial materials, and windlaid materials.
Collection also includes several publications by faculty involved with the program and others. Also includes equipment used for viewing film reels.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies.; Skylab Program.; United States. Environmental Protection Agency.
Titles:
Remote sensing.
Subjects:
Aerial photography.; Artificial satellites in remote sensing.; Eutrophication.; Landforms.; Photographic interpretation.; Photography, Military.
Places:
Finger Lakes (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Remote-sensing images.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Skylab
Subseries Ia. Skylab Documents
Subseries Ib. Skylab II Roll Film
Subseries Ic. Skylab III Roll Film
Unknown locations
Subseries Id. Skylab IV Roll Film
Unknown locations
Series II. Cornell/EPA
Subseries IIa. Documents
Subseries IIb. Mission 278 Roll Film and Documents
Subseries IIc. Mission 280 Roll Film and Documents
Subseries IId. Fairchild Mission I Roll Film
Subseries IIe. Fairchild Mission III Roll Film
Subseries IIf. RADC Flights Foll Film
Subseries IIg. Unknown Missions Roll Film
Series III. Additional Roll Film and Documents
Subseries IIIa. Documents
Subseries IIIb. Mission 186
Subseries IIIc. Mission 192
Subseries IIId. Mission 235
Subseries IIIe. Mission 253
Subseries IIIf. Mission 258 and 337
Subseries IIIg. Mission 361 and 367
Subseries IIIh. Mission 382 and 387
Subseries IIIi. Mission 404 and 430
Subseries IIIj. AT
Subseries IIIk. New York State Lakes
Subseries IIIl. Texas VI
Subseries IIIm. Texas VII
Subseries IIIn. High Altitude mission 4
Subseries IIIo. Unknown missions
Series IV. Landforms
Series V. Documents and Publications
Subseries Va. General
Subseries Vb. Cornell Publications and Reports, Published in Ithaca
Subseries Vc. Panama Project
Subseries Vd. Puerto Rico Project
Series VI. Photographs
Series VII. Viewers
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Skylab
  - Subseries I a. Skylab Documents
    - Skylab photo data binder, lab copy (Box 43, Folder 13)
      Section 1: Roll Numbers and Film/Filter/Band
      Section II: Exposure Data
      Section III: Filter Data
      Section IV: Flight Film and Processing
      Section V: Dupe Film and Processing
  - Subseries I b. Skylab II Roll Film
    Roll numbers that appear together are located in one canister.
    - 70m News Loop (Box 1)
    - Rolls 6, 12, 18, June, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Roll 546, Caribbean, June 11, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 547, Bolivia, June 14, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 550, Brazil, Jun 9, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 556, Central America, June 14, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 557, June 14, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 559, Wyoming, June 13, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 560, Caribbean, June 13, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 561, Alabama, Florida, June 13, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 562, Iowa, Illinois, June 10, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 563, Puerto Rico, June 9, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 564, June 14, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 565, June 14, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 566, May 30, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 567, June 11, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 568, May 30, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 569, June 11, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 570, June 2, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 572, June 12, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 574, June 3, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 576, June 2, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 577, June 5, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 578, June 12, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 579, June 3, 1973 (Box 51)
    - Roll 580, June 9, 1973 (Box 51)
  - Subseries I c. Skylab III Roll Film
    - Brazil, roll 19, August, 1973 (Box 2)
    - California; Mexico; Arizona; Colorado; Texas, roll 27, September, 1973 (Box 2)
    - California; Mexico; Arizona; Colorado; Texas, roll 27, September, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Clouds over the Pacific; Washington, Willapa Harbor; Oregon; Idaho; Utah; Alberta, roll 83, August, 1973 (Box 2)
    - North America, Australia, roll 22, August, 1973 (Box 1)
    - North America, Australia, roll 28, August, 1973 (Box 1)
    - North America, Australia, roll 84, August, 1973 (Box 2)
    - North America, Japan, roll 46, September, 1973 (Box 3)
    - North America, Japan, roll 88, September, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Pacific Ocean off Mexico; California; Mexico; Nevada; Arizona; Colorado, roll 85, October, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Pacific Ocean off Mexico; California; Mexico; Nevada; Arizona; Colorado, roll 85, October, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Unknown Locations
      - Roll 20 (Box 2)
      - Roll 21, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 23 (Box 36)
      - Roll 24 (Box 3)
      - Roll 25, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 26, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 27, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 29, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 30, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 31, September, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 32, September, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 33, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 35, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 36, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 37, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 38, September, 1973 (Box 1)
      - Roll 39, September, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Roll 41, September, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Roll 42, September, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Roll 43, September, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Roll 44, September, 1973 (Box 2)
      - Roll 45, September, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 47, September, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 48, September, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 964, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 523, 535, 573, 574, 582, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 529, 542, 540, 545, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 534, 538, 555, 559, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Roll 503, 504, 509, 510, 512, 514, 517, 528, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll 541, 560, 569, 570, 579, 593, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll 501, 531, 544, 551, 562, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll 536, 549, 556, 565, 588, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll CX 10, 11, 25, 26, 27, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll CX 12, 13, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll CI 99, 100, 101, 102, 103, 105, 106, 107, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Roll W.O. 1538 (Box 5)
  - Subseries I d. Skylab IV Roll Film
    - Brazil, roll A1 (Box 9)
    - North America, South America, roll 68 (Box 8)
    - Pacific, North America, roll 70 (Box 7)
    - Pacific, North America, roll 90 (Box 8)
    - Pacific, North America, roll 92 (Box 8)
    - Pacific, North America, roll 93 (Box 5)
    - Pacific, North America, roll 94 (Box 9)
    - Pacific, North America, South America, roll 76 (Box 8)
    - Pacific, North America, South America, Japan, roll 64 (Box 6)
    - Pacific, North America, South America, two copies of roll 52 (Box 6)
    - Pacific, Southeast Asia, Australia, roll 91 (Box 8)
    - South America, roll 49 (Box 5)
    - Unknown Locations
      - Roll A2, February, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Roll A3 (Box 9)
      - Roll A4, February, 1974 (Box 34)
      - Roll A5, February, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Roll A6 (Box 9)
      - Roll 1B, two copies, February, 1974 (Box 7)
      - Roll 2B, two copies, February, 1974 (Box 9)
      - Roll 3B, February, 1974 (Box 5)
      - Roll 4B, February, 1974 (Box 5)
      - Roll 5B, February, 1974 (Box 5)
      - Roll 6B, February, 1974 (Box 9)
      - Roll 50 (Box 5)
      - Roll 51 (Box 6)
      - Roll 51 (Box 36)
      - Roll 53 (Box 6)
      - Roll 54 (Box 6)
      - Roll 55 (Box 6)
      - Roll 56 (Box 6)
      - Roll 57, February, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Roll 58, February, 1974 (Box 36)
      - Roll 59 (Box 6)
      - Roll 60 (Box 6)
      - Roll 61 (Box 10)
      - Roll 62 (Box 5)
      - Roll 63 (Box 6)
      - Roll 65 (Box 6)
      - Roll 66 (Box 5)
      - Roll 67 (Box 9)
      - Roll 69 (Box 9)
      - Roll 71 (Box 7)
      - Roll 72 (Box 7)
      - Roll 73 (Box 7)
      - Roll 74 (Box 8)
      - Roll 75 (Box 9)
      - Roll 77 (Box 8)
      - Roll 78 (Box 10)
      - Roll 89 (Box 9)
      - Roll 695, 698, 694, 696, 697 (Box 5)
      - Roll 661, 654, 655, 657, 662, 664 (Box 5)
      - Roll 679, 681, 688, 658, 687, 674, 659 (Box 7)
      - Roll 660, 680, 683, 682, 685, 690 (Box 7)
      - Roll 667, 668, 665, 699 (Box 7)
      - Roll 656, 676, 678, 686, 689, 691, 671, 673 (Box 7)
      - Roll CX 17, 45, 47, 51, 52 (Box 9)
      - Roll CX 18, 46, 50 (Box 9)
- Series II. Cornell/EPA
  - Subseries II a. Documents
    - Progress report, April, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Fairchild Missions and RADC flight logs, data, and roll film index (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II b. Mission 278 Roll Film and Documents
    Objective: to determine the applicability of remote sensing for identifying outflows into Canadarago Lake, NY. Three Medium-altitude flights.
    - Mission 278 flight logs, data, and summary (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Canadarago, roll 11, May, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Roll 12, May, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Roll 13, May, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 14, May, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Roll 15, May, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Roll 16, May, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 502, June, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 601, May, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 601, May, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Subseries II c. Mission 280 Roll Film and Documents
    Three medium-altitude flights.
    - Mission 280 flight logs, data, and summary, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Canadarago, roll 24, August, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Canadarago, roll 25, August, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Roll 26, August, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 27, August, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Roll 28, August, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Roll 29, August, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Subseries II d. Fairchild Mission I
    - Flight SO 242
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 1-66)
        South to north
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 67-95)
        Montezuma
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 96-139)
        Montezuma, south to East Varick
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 140-146)
        East Varick, North
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 147-182)
      - Owasco, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 183-186)
        West to east
      - Skaneateles, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 187-218)
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 219-285)
        Sheldrake, south
      - Canadarago, July, 1973 (Box 35, Frame 286-294)
  - Subseries II e. Fairchild Mission III
    - Flight SO 242
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 1-71)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 72-81)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 82-93)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 94-134)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 135-175)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 176-205)
      - Skaneateles, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 206-212)
      - Owasco, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 213-217)
      - Great Gully, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 218-236)
    - Flight FE 3432
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 1-71)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 72-81)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 82-93)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 94-120)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 121-184)
        overlapping overexposed images
    - Flight 2443
      - Onondaga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 1-4)
      - Onondaga, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 5-21)
      - Canadarago, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 22-43)
      - Great Gully, September, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 44-59)
    - Flight 2448
      - Duplicate, September, 1973 (Box 35)
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 1-71)
        Sheldrake, south to inlet
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 72-81)
        East across mouth of inlet
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 94-134)
        West across lake just north of previous run
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 82-93)
        Athens Pt., north along east shore to Jct. of Seneca River and Erie Canal
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 135-175(?))
        Montezuma, just south of NYS Thruway, south to Cayuga Junction
      - Cayuga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 175-206)
        Montezuma, from finish of last run north to jct. of Rte. 414 and NYS thruway
      - Skaneateles, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 207-213)
        East to west from Five Mile Pt.
      - Owasco, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 214-218)
        East to west across lake to Glenwood Beach
      - Great Gully, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 219-237)
      - Onondaga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 1-9)
        North to south
      - Onondaga, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 10-15)
        South to North
      - Canadarago, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 16-32)
        South to north along east shore
      - Canadarago, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 33-54)
        North to south along west shore and middle of lake
      - Water (?), September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 55-57)
      - Great Gully, September, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 58-73)
        Cayuga Lake, east to Jct. of Great Gully and Rt. 34B
  - Subseries II f. RADC Flights
    - Flight FE 3432
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 1-8)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 9-17)
        Union Springs, South
      - Unlabelled, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 18-24)
        Union Springs
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 25-33)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 34-37)
        East shore, South Crossing to west shore
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 38-49)
        Southern end
      - Unlabelled, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 50-51)
        East shore (at Quarry south, crossing to west shore, to Ithaca)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 52-83)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 84-104)
        West shore, north to Montezuma
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 105-143)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 144-164)
        Sheldrake Pt. south along Cayuga
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 165-172)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 173-180)
        Fly west to east across lake at Lake Ridge Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 181-188)
        Fly east to west at Lake Ridge Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 189-195)
        East to west to Taughannock Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 196-201)
        West to east at Taughannock Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 202-207)
        East to west at Glenwood Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 208-212)
        East to west just north of inlet
      - Skaneateles, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 213-228)
        East to west across inlet
      - Canadarago, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 229-232)
    - Flight 2443
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 1-8)
        Union Springs, south
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 9-17)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 18-24)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 25-33)
        East shore, south crossing to west shore
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 34-37)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 38-49)
        East shore at Quarry, south, crossing to west shore, to Ithaca
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 50-51)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 52-83)
        West shore north to Montezuma
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 84-104)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 105-125)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 126-133)
        Lake Ridge Pt.
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 134-140)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 142-178)
      - Cayuga, July, August, 1973 (Box 36, Frame 179-220)
    - Flight 2448
      - Unlabelled, September, 1973 (Box 36)
        Duplicate
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 1-9)
        Center pass of lake beginning over Ithaca
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 15-34)
        Center pass, Ithaca to Willets
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 35-41)
        Willets to Montezuma
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 42-73)
        Montezuma: NE side
      - Unlabelled, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 74-75)
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 76-107)
        Montezuma: N. Center
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 108-134)
        Montezuma: NW side
      - Cayuga, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 135-137)
        E-W over mouth of inlet
      - Skaneateles, July, 1973 (Box 32, Frame 138-154)
  - Subseries II g. Unknown Missions
    - 2443 Vineyards, August, 1975 (Box 33)
    - 2448 Finger Lakes, May, 1975 (Box 31)
    - 2448 Duplicate, December, 1974 (Box 32)
    - FLT 11-12, 13, April, 1975 (Box 31)
    - Thermal IR, June, 1975 (Box 31)
      Sites 1-6
    - Thermal IR, December, 1974 (Box 36)
      Sites 1-10, 10-14
    - Unlabelled (Box 36)
    - Unlabelled (Box 35)
    - Cornell EPA, April, 1975 (Box 35)
    - CIR, September, 1974 (Box 35)
    - CIR (Box 33)
      Niagara, Erie
    - CIR, March, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Cornell EPA, March, 1975 (Box 33)
    - CIR, April, 1975 (Box 33)
      Number 15
    - Lakes, August, 1973 (Box 32)
    - CIR, December, 1974 (Box 32)
    - Color AM, April, 1975 (Box 34)
    - CIR, April, 1975 (Box 34)
    - Broome County Landfill, June, 1975 (Box 34)
    - CIR, June, 1975 (Box 34)
    - CIR, June, 1975 (Box 34)
- Series III. Additional Roll Film and Documents
  - Subseries III a. Documents
    - Mission 190 and 191 cataloging and index reports (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Mission 197 cataloging and indexing report (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Summary catalogue, missions 155-191, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Summary catalogue, missions 192-225, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Mission 247 project report, RS-14 reference source (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Apollo 9 High Altitude Underflights summaries (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Index cards of flights by state, NASA flight listing cross reference by state, high altitude study (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Flights logs and camera correlation information (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Project support plans for SRT X154, SRT X163, SRT OAA 0359 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Subseries III b. Mission 186
    - Cataloguing and indexing report (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Mission 186, roll 1, October, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Mission 186, roll 3, October, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Subseries III c. Mission 192
    - Cataloging index report (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Mission 192, roll 11, January, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Subseries III d. Mission 235
    St. Lawrence, Albany, Schenectady, Wayne County.
    - Project reports, flight logs (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Project reports, flight logs (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Roll 69, June, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Roll 72, June, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Roll 73, June, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Roll 76, June, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Roll 85, June, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Roll 93, June, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Roll 97, June, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Roll 98, June, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Roll 508, June, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Roll 509, June, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Subseries III e. Mission 253
    - Roll 55 and 62 (Box 12)
    - Roll 56 and 63 (Box 12)
    - Roll 57, August, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll 59, August, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Roll 60, August, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Roll 61, August, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Roll 228, August, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Subseries III f. Mission 258 and 337
    - Mission 258, roll 47, December, 1973 (Box 13)
      St. Lawrence
    - Mission 337, roll 2, April, 1976 (Box 16)
      Cornell Campus
    - Mission 337, roll 6, April, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Mission 337, roll 7, April, 1976 (Box 15)
    - Mission 337, roll unnumbered, April, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Subseries III g. Mission 361 and 367
    - Mission 361, roll 9, June, 1977 (Box 16)
      Hammondsport
    - Mission 367, roll 3, 1977 (Box 17)
      Vineyards
    - Mission 367, roll 4, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Subseries III h. Mission 382 and 387
    - Mission 382 flight log, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Mission 382, roll 2, 1978 (Box 19)
      Finger Lakes
    - Mission 382, roll 3, 1978 (Box 19)
    - Mission 387, roll 9, August, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Mission 387, roll 10, August, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Subseries III i. Mission 404 and 430
    - Mission 404 flight log and project support plan, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Mission 404, roll 1, June, 1979 (Box 18)
      Adirondacks
    - Mission 404, roll 8, June, 1979 (Box 18)
    - Mission 404, roll unnumbered, June, 1979 (Box 18)
    - Mission 430, roll 13, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Mission 430, roll 14, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Subseries III j. AT
    - Roll 391A, 1968 (Box 20)
    - Roll 391C, 1968 (Box 20)
    - Roll 486A, 1969 (Box 20)
    - Roll 486B, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Subseries III k. New York State Lakes
    - Flight index cards, flight summary reports for 72-067, 72-118, 72-145, and 72-146, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 13)